Guide to the Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IX: Productions
  - Subseries IX.1: Alphabetic List
    - An Act of Virtue -- -- And the Angels Sang SEE My Three Angels -- -- At Rise SEE Misc. -- -- Big Boy SEE Misc. -- -- Better than Ever SEE Boy Meets Girl -- -- Black Stemmed Cherries SEE Misc. -- -- Blinski SEE Leave it to Me under Sweeney -- -- Borrowed Love SEE Misc. -- -- Boy Meets Girl -- -- Can Can SEE Misc. -- -- Cat and the Fiddle SEE Misc. -- -- Child's Play SEE Festival -- -- Clear All Wires SEE Leave it to Me -- -- A Comedy with Music SEE Misc. -- -- Comfort with Apples -- -- Comrade X SEE Leave it to Me UNDER Clear All Wires -- -- Countess and Conductor SEE The Orient Express -- -- La Cuisine des Anges SEE My Three Angels -- -- Dear Mr. Sweeney SEE Leave it to Me UNDER Sweeney -- -- Deus Anges Sont Venus SEE My Three Angels -- -- Eine Schoene Bescherung SEE My Three Angels -- -- The Enchanted Nutcracker -- -- An English Play SEE Misc. -- -- Ex-Lover SEE Once There was a Russian -- -- Ex-Officer SEE Solitaire Man -- -- Ex-Officer X SEE Solitaire Man -- -- Female Human Being SEE Of Human Bondage -- -- Festival -- -- Gambling SEE Misc. -- -- The Gay Bride SEE Misc. -- -- A Gentleman's Gentleman SEE Misc. -- -- The Golden State -- -- Happy SEE Boy Meets Girl -- -- Hizzoner SEE Papa -- -- How to make a Woman Happy SEE Two Blind Mice -- -- I've Got a Book SEE Miss Swan Expects -- -- Kiss Me Kate -- -- A Kiss for Tomorrow SEE Misc. -- -- Kuess Mich Kaetchen SEE Kiss Me Kate -- -- Lady Liz SEE Mrs. A. -- -- The Lamplighter SEE Comfort with Apples -- -- Lawyer Lady and Thief SEE The Night is Young -- -- Leave it to Me -- -- Leo McCrary #2 SEE My Favorite Wife -- -- Liebe=x SEE Under the Sycamore Tree -- -- Life with the Wooleys SEE Misc. -- -- Look to the Ant SEE Under the Sycamore Tree -- -- The Lost Soldier SEE Misc. -- -- Manna Falls for Moses SEE The Shyster -- -- Manhatten Miracle SEE The Night is Young -- -- Meet the Wife SEE My Favorite Wife -- -- Miracle in Manhatten SEE The Night is Young -- -- Miss Swan Expects -- -- Move Over Darling SEE My Favorite Wife -- -- Mr. Broadway -- -- Mr. Jennings SEE Solitaire Man -- -- Mr. Jenkins SEE Solitaire Man -- -- Mr. King's Case -- -- Mrs. A. -- -- My Favorite Wife -- -- My Three Angels -- -- The Night is Young -- -- Nucleus SEE Out West it's Different -- -- Nize Baby SEE Misc. -- -- Of Human Bondage -- -- Once there was a Russian -- -- One Man's Venus -- -- The Orient Express -- -- Out West it's Different -- -- Perfect Pitch SEE Festival -- -- Pincus SEE Poppa -- -- Play it by ear SEE Festival -- -- The Play's the Thing SEE Misc. -- -- Pleasures and Palaces SEE Once there was a Russian -- -- Poppa -- -- Portrait of Boy with Ladder SEE Out West it's Different -- -- Potemkin SEE Once there was a Russian -- -- Pousse Toi Cherie SEE My Favorite Wife -- -- The Prince and Mr. Jones SEE Once there was a Russian -- -- The Princess and the Pauper -- -- Private Jones SEE Once there was a Russian OR War Song -- -- Eine Schoene Bescherung SEE My Three Angels -- -- The Shyster -- -- Sister Carrie SEE Misc. -- -- Sisters SEE Misc. -- -- Sky Trapped SEE Misc. -- -- The Solitaire Man -- -- Something's Got to Give SEE My Favorite Wife -- -- Spring Song -- -- Spring Song SEE Misc. (this short script seems unrelated to the above--has different plot, different characters) -- -- Swing High Sweeney SEE Leave it to Me UNDER Sweeney -- -- Sweeney SEE Leave it to Me -- -- Theodora SEE Misc. -- -- There Goes the Ballgame SEE An Act of Virtue -- -- Trousers to Match SEE Miss Swan Expects -- -- Trousers to Match SEE Short Stories and Articles, Bella (this story seems unrelated to the play of the same name) -- -- Twisting the Law SEE The Shyster -- -- Two Acts of Virtue SEE An Act of Virtue -- -- Two Angels Have Come SEE My Three Angels -- -- Two Blind Mice -- -- Under the Sycamore Tree -- -- Unmarried Father SEE Misc. -- -- Vogues SEE Misc. -- -- The War Song -- -- The Way of a Hen SEE Festival -- -- Weekend at the Waldorf -- -- White Girl -- -- Wings SEE The Solitaire Man -- -- Woman Bites Dog -- -- Woman Overboard SEE My Favorite Wife -- -- Young Man with a Ladder SEE Out West it's Different -- -- You're Only Young Twice SEE Misc. -- -- Zwei Blinde Huener SEE Two Blind Mice
  - Subseries IX.2: An Act of Virtue
    - Correspondence -- Background (clippings about nuns) -- Worksheets (2 folders) -- Scripts: version A (2 copies); version B (2 copies); version C -- Financial (estimated production budget (Box 8)
  - Subseries IX.3: Boy Meets Girl
    - Correspondence, 1935-1956, (24 folders, ) (Box 9)
      [Includes opening night telegrams, correspondence re. printed book]
    - Correspondence, 1957-1980, (21 folders, ) (Box 10)
    - Worksheets, (2 folders, )
    - Scripts: -- --Script A/2 (prompt script, annotated) -- --Script A (2 copies) -- --Script B
    - Script C -- Script D (film) -- Script E (film) -- Script F (film, final) -- Script E (Italian, annotated) -- Script G (German, annotated) -- Script H (German) (Box 11)
    - Legal: -- --contracts [includes contracts r.e. BMG game, re. legal protection afforded title]
    - Financial, (7 folders, ) (Box 12)
      [Includes financial information for British production, box office receipts from tour, misc.)]
    - Photos -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Other (includes menu from Hollywood dinner, list of places BMG was performed, misc.) -- Softcover printed books: 2 copies version 1; 2 copies version 2 (includes Spring Song); 1 copy version 2 with inscription and annotations -- Hardcover printed books: 2 copies version 1; 3 copies version 2 (includes Spring Song) all inscribed (Box 13)
  - Subseries IX.4: Comfort Me with Apples
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets (2 folders) -- Scripts: -- -- Script A ("The Lamplighter") -- -- Script B (2 copies) -- -- Script C (2 copies) (Box 14)
  - Subseries IX.5: The Enchanted Nutcracker
    - Correspondence -- Background information (playbill from Nutcracker ballet) -- Summaries (2 copies) -- Worksheets -- Scripts: Script A (2 copies); Script B (revision 9/5/61, 2 copies); Script C (revision 9/28/61, 2 copies) -- Legal (includes contracts, legal correspondence) -- Financial (includes income statements) -- Photos (includes photos of rehearsals, of production with printed descriptions) -- Clippings -- Other (includes blocking and taping schedules, piece of tape) (Box 15)
  - Subseries IX.6: Festival
    - Correspondence r.e. Perfect Pitch -- Correspondence--opening night telegrams -- Correspondence 1950-1970 (3 folders) -- Worksheets for Perfect Pitch (2 folders) -- Worksheets -- Summary -- Scripts: -- -- Script A ("The Way of a Hen," 2 copies) -- -- Script B ("Perfect Pitch," annotated) -- -- Script C ("Perfect Pitch") (Box 16)
    - Script D ("Perfect Pitch," 5 copies, 3 annotated) -- Script E (2 copies, both annotated) -- Script F (2 copies, 1 annotated) -- Script G (incomplete, annotated) (Box 17)
    - Script H (incomplete) -- Script I (2 copies, 1 annotated) -- Legal: -- --Contracts for Way of a Hen -- -- Contracts for Perfect Pitch; Contracts -- Financial -- Photos (of finished production) -- Playbills: Perfect Pitch; Festival -- Clippings: Way of a Hen; Perfect Pitch; Festival; Typewritten reviews -- Other (includes scene design, audience survey, interview questions, misc.) -- Printed Material: Printed scripts--"Play it by Ear" (Box 18)
  - Subseries IX.7: The Golden State
    - Correspondence -- Scripts: Script A (3 copies, 1 annotated); Script B (3 copies, i annotated) -- Financial: Box office statements; Book sale receipts; Budget; Production fees; Prop information; Financial correspondence; Manager's account statements; Cashbooks; Income tax information (Box 19)
    - Financial--vouchers, etc. (2 folders) -- Legal (contracts) -- Photos (includes rehearsal photos, Spewacks at rehearsal, finished production) -- Clippings -- Other (company information, misc.) -- Printed Material: Softcover printed scripts (2 copies) (Box 20)
  - Subseries IX.8: Kiss Me Kate
    - Correspondence, 1948-1958 (Box 21)
      [Includes opening night telegrams,13 folders]
    - Correspondence, 1959-1962, (8 folders, ) (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1965, (8 folders, ) (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968, (9 folders, ) (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1981, (16 folders, ) (Box 25)
    - Background Material: The Taming of the Shrew in hardback, 2 copies; The Taming of the Shrew, typescript; Hallmark Hall of Fame t.v. script of Shrew, annotated, 2 copies; Worksheets for Hallmark script (non-Spewack) -- Worksheets (2 folders) -- Summaries -- Song lyrics -- Song lyrics revisions -- Script fragments (Box 26)
    - Scripts--bound: Script A (5 copies, 2 annotated, 1 labeled British); Script B (2 copies, 1 annotated); Script C (3 copies, 1 annotated, 1 labeled Final) (Box 27)
    - Scripts--for television: Script D (2 copies, both incomplete); Script E (Hallmark Hall of Fame, 3 copies, 2 annotated); Script F (BBC, 2 copies, 1 annotated) (Box 28)
    - Scripts--foreign: Script G (Danish); Script H (French); Script I (Icelandic); Script J (Italian, 2 copies); Script K (Swedish) (Box 29)
    - Script in Braille (Box 30)
    - Legal: -- --contracts: -- Hurok Attractions -- Hallmark Hall of Fame -- Scholastic Book Services -- Knopf -- Film -- Argentina -- Australia -- Belgium (Brussels) -- Czechoslovakia -- England (BBC) -- England (Sadler's Wells Opera, London) -- England (St. Subber and Samuel Ayers) -- England (director's) -- France (translation) -- France (Paris) -- France (Societe des Auteurs) -- Germany-Austria Switzerland -- Greece -- Holland (SEBA) -- Italy -- Japan -- Mexico -- Norway-Sweden-Denmark-Poland -- Yougoslavia -- Poland -- Yugoslavia -- -- Financial (3 folders misc.) (Box 31)
    - Financial, (3 (misc.) folders, )
    - Financial, (8 misc. folders, ) (Box 32)
    - Photos: -- --negatives -- --Cole Porter and Bella -- --Ingrid Bergman, Bella, Bob Wright -- --Broadway production -- --Wagner College production -- --North Shore Music Theater production -- --Seattle production -- --Century Theater production -- --Misc. -- --The Taming of the Shrew (non-Spewack) (Box 33)
    - Photos--foreign productions: -- --Posters for foreign productions: -- --Argentina, Buenos Aires -- --Austria, Vienna -- --Belgium, Brussels -- --Canada, Toronto -- --Czechoslovakia, Prague -- --Denmark, Copenhagen -- --England, Sadler's Wells Opera, London -- --England, BBC -- --Germany, Frankfurt -- --Germany -- --Holland -- --Hungary -- --Iceland, Reykjavik -- --Israel -- --Italy, Trieste -- --Japan, Tokyo -- --Norway, Oslo -- --Poland, Warsaw -- --Sweden, Malmo -- --Turkey, Ankara -- --Yugoslavia, Zagreb (Box 34)
    - Playbills (in English) (Box 35)
    - Playbills (in foreign languages) (Box 36)
    - Clippings (reviews and references--includes printed articles, ads, typescripts): -- Anta Album references -- ABC t.v. productions reviews -- Bergman, Wright, Bella--interview typescript -- Century Theater reviews -- Civic Light Opera reviews -- Hallmark Hall of Fame t.v. production reviews -- Kabuki Theater reviews -- Elizabeth Larner clippings -- "Much Ado About Kate" article by Bella -- "My Life with Shakespeare" article by Bella -- New York City Center reviews -- Playboy article mentioning KMK -- Cole Porter clippings, etc. -- Shubert Theater reviews -- The Taming of the Shrew film reviews (some mention KMK) -- Theater Arts cover -- "We've Been There Before" article by Bella -- "Woman Behind Girl Scout Cookies and Kiss Me Kate" -- Misc. references -- Misc. reviews -- Misc. reviews--financial (box office intake lists) -- Misc. typescripts of reviews -- Misc. typescripts of reviews by Bella -- Misc. retrospective reviews (Box 37)
    - Clippings--foreign: -- --Argentina (Buenos Aires) (typescript) -- --Austria (Vienna) -- --Belgium (Brussels) (typescript and printed) -- --Czechoslovakia -- --England (BBC) -- --France -- --Germany (typescript and printed) -- --Holland (typescript) -- --Hungary (Budapest) -- --Israel (typescript and printed) -- --Italy (Trieste) -- --Italy (Verona) -- --Poland (typescript and printed) -- --Soviet Union -- --Sweden (Malmo) -- --Turkey -- --Yugoslavia (typescript and printed) (Box 38)
    - Other: -- --Publicity package -- --"Under Discussion: Shakespeare" script -- --KMK tour information -- --New York Public Library Exhibit -- --Production information -- --Misc.
    - Printed Material: -- --Knopf script (1 copy, 1 photocopy) -- --German script ("Kuess Mich Kaetchen") (2 copies) -- --Dutch script (2 copies) -- --Japanese script -- --Script printed in Theater Arts Magazine -- --Book jackets for Knopf edition (Box 39)
  - Subseries IX.9: Leave it to Me as Clear All Wires
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets -- Scripts: -- --Script A (annotated) -- -- Script B (annotated) -- --Script C (annotated) -- --Script D -- --Script E (incomplete) -- --Script F (2 copies, both incomplete) -- Legal--contracts -- Financial--box office statements, misc. -- Photos--Spewacks and cast members -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Printed Material--photocopy of printed script (Box 40)
  - Subseries IX.10: Leave it to Me as Sweeney
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets -- Scripts: Script A ("Dear Mr. Sweeney"); Script B ("Swing High Sweeney"); Script C ("Swing High Sweeney," annotated); Script D (2 copies); Script E; Script F (2 copies) -- Financial--misc. -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Other: Summary for "Blinski," an adaptation of "Sweeney" for the Marx Brothers--4 copies, 2 annotated. (Box 41)
  - Subseries IX.11: Leave it to Me as Leave it to Me
    - Correspondence -- Summary (2 copies) -- Scripts: -- --Script A (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- --Script B (2 copies, 1 annotated) -- Financial--box office statements, misc. (2 folders) -- Legal -- Photos--of performance -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Other--production information, misc. (Box 42)
  - Subseries IX.12: Miss Swan Expects
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets -- Summary (2 copies) -- Scripts: -- --Script A -- --Script B (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- Financial--box office statements, misc. -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Printed Material: Printed script Trousers to Match, 2 copies (Box 43)
  - Subseries IX.13: Mr. Broadway
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets (2 folders) -- Summary -- Scripts: -- --Script A -- --Script B (2 copies, both annotated) -- Legal--contracts -- Financial--misc. -- Clippings -- Other--rehearsal schedules, misc. (Box 44)
  - Subseries IX.14: Mr. King's Case
    - Correspondence -- Script--4 copies, 2 annotated (Box 45:)
  - Subseries IX.15: Mrs. A.
    - Correspondence (2 folders) -- Background--clippings re. Gertrude Lawrence -- Worksheets (2 folders) -- Summary ("Lady Liz") -- Scripts: -- --Script A (2 copies, both annotated) -- -- Script B (2 copies) (Box 46)
    - Scripts: -- --Script C (2 copies) -- --Script D (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- Legal--contracts (2 folders) -- Financial--misc. -- Photos--possible actresses to play leading role -- Clippings: re. Julie Andrews; re. production -- Other: Notes toward production; Song lyrics (Box 47)
  - Subseries IX.16: My Favorite Wife
    - Correspondence -- Background: -- --Script A ("Move Over Darling" by Hal Kanter and Jack Sher) -- Scripts: -- --Script B (McCarey #2 or "Woman Overboard") -- --Script C (incomplete, out of order) -- --Script D -- Legal--contracts -- Clippings (Box 48)
  - Subseries IX.17: My Three Angels
    - Correspondence, 1952-1985, (33 folders, ) (Box 49)
      [Includes correspondence with Hugh "Binkie" Beaumont 1953-1954]
    - Background: -- --Subber translation of Husson's play -- --Millington translation of Husson's play -- --Pierre's adaptation of Husson's play (French) -- --Translation of Pierre's adaptation (2 copies) -- Worksheets (2 folders) -- Summary (2 copies, 1 annotated) (Box 50)
    - Scripts: -- --Script A -- --Script B -- --Script C -- --Script D "And the Angels Sang" 3 copies, 1 annotated (Box 51)
    - Scripts: -- --Script E ("We're No Angels" film) -- --Script F (for t.v. 2 copies, 1 annotated) -- --Script G (for BBC radio 2 copies) -- --Script H (Hebrew) -- --Script I (Spanish) (Box 52)
    - Legal: -- --Contracts (3 folders) -- --Paramount squabble: -- -- Trial transcript -- --Background for case -- --Misc. (correspondence, etc.) -- --Misc. (Box 53)
    - Financial: -- --Information re. audit -- --British production -- --Australian production -- --Misc. (3 folders) (Box 54)
    - Photos--of various performances -- Playbills: English and Foreign -- Clippings: Reviews of Film; Reviews of t.v. production; Misc.; Misc. foreign -- Other: Production information--list of cities for road tour, press releases, etc. -- Printed Material: -- --Husson play "La Cuisine des Anges" in French -- --German version of Husson play: "Eine Schoene Bescherung" -- --Script of My Three Angels in Theater Arts Magazine (2 copies) -- --Printed scripts of My Three Angels in book form: Uncorrected proof with annotations; Edition A (2 copies); Edition B (2 copies); Edition C (3 copies, 1 inscribed and annotated) (Box 55)
  - Subseries IX.18: The Night is Young
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets (2 folders) -- Scripts: -- --Script A (2 copies:"Lawyer, Lady and Thief" and "Miracle in Manhattan") -- --Script B -- --Script C (screenplay, first draft) -- --Script D (screenplay, final draft, incomplete, 2 copies) -- Legal--contracts -- Clippings (Box 56)
  - Subseries IX.19: Of Human Bondage
    - Correspondence -- Background--information re. historical London -- Worksheets (3 folders) -- Scripts: -- --Script A ("Female Human Being," 2 copies) -- --Script B (2 copies) -- --Script C -- Other--song lyrics -- Clippings (Box 57)
  - Subseries IX.20: Once There Was a Russian
    - Correspondence 1928-1975 (17 folders) -- Background--historical information about John Paul Jones, etc. -- Worksheets (1-3 of 6 folders) (Box 58)
    - Worksheets (4-6 of 6 folders) -- Summary ("A Russian Story" 2 versions) -- Scripts: -- --Script A ("Ex-Lover" 2 copies, both annotated) -- --Script B ("Pleasures and Palaces" 2 copies, 1 annotated) -- --Script C ("Pleasures and Palaces" annotated) (Box 59)
    - --Script D (2 copies, both annotated, 1 labeled "Ex-Lover") -- --Script E ("Ex-Lover," annotated) -- --Script F ("Ex-Lover," annotated) -- --Script G (untitled, annotated) -- --Script H (untitled, annotated, 2 copies, 1 incomplete) -- --Script I ("The Prince and Mr. Jones," copies 1-2 of 7, 1 annotated) (Box 60)
    - Script I ("The Prince and Mr. Jones," copies 3-7 of 7, 3-5 annotated) (Box 61)
    - Legal: Contracts; Misc. -- Financial--box office statements, etc. -- Photos: -- --Posters, Performance with Walter Matthau -- --negatives -- --Ari Kutai, Israeli actor trying for role -- Playbills: -- --The Prince and Mr. Jones -- --Once There Was a Russian -- Clippings -- Other--rehearsal schedule, actors' phone list, etc. -- Printed Material: "The Prince and Mr. Jones" script in book form (Box 62)
  - Subseries IX.21: One Man's Venus
    - Correspondence -- Background: -- --"The Tinted Venus" story by F. Ansley, 2 copies -- --Untitled script by Perelman/Nash/Weill, 2 copies -- --"One Touch of Venus" script by Kunitz -- Worksheets -- Scripts: -- --Script A (annotated, not in order) -- --Script B (3 copies, 2 annotated) -- --Script C (2 copies) -- Legal--contracts -- Clippings (Box 63)
  - Subseries IX.22: The Orient Express
    - Correspondence -- Summary: -- --Version A (2 copies) -- --Version B (3 copies, 1 annotated, "for the Astaires") -- Script (3 copies, 2 labeled "The Countess and the Conductor") -- Clippings--typescript review (Box 64)
  - Subseries IX.23: Out West it's Different
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets (3 folders ) -- Scripts: -- --Script A ("Young Man with a Ladder" 2 copies, 1 annotated) -- --Script B ("Portrait of Boy with Ladder" 2 copies) -- --Script C (2 copies) (Box 65)
    - --Script D (untitled) -- --Script E (annotated) -- --Script F (untitled) -- --Script G -- --Script H (2 copies) -- Legal--contracts -- Financial--report -- Playbills -- Clippings (Box 66)
  - Subseries IX.24: Poppa
    - Correspondence -- Worksheets -- Summary -- Scripts: -- --Script A (2 copies) -- --Script B -- --Script C ("Hizzoner" 2 copies, 1 incomplete) -- --Script D (Italian) -- Legal--contracts -- Financial--box office statements -- Playbills -- Clippings--Italian review, typescript translation -- Printed Material--script in book form, 2 copies (Box 67)
  - Subseries IX.25: The Princess and the Pauper
    - Correspondence -- Background: Story by Lynn Root and Frank Fenton -- Worksheets -- Scripts: -- --Script A (annotated, incomplete) -- --Script B (film, incomplete) -- --Script C (film, 2 copies) -- Clippings (Box 68)
  - Subseries IX.26: The Solitaire Man
    - Correspondence -- Summaries: -- --Summary A (2 copies, 1 annotated) -- --Summary B (2 copies) -- --Summary C (German, 2 copies) -- --Summary D (annotated) -- Scripts: -- --Script A (annotated, incomplete) -- --Script B (annotated, incomplete) -- --Script C (annotated, incomplete) -- --Script D (2 copies, both annotated, 1 incomplete) -- --Script E -- --Script F (2 copies) -- --Script G (2 copies) -- Financial--misc. -- Playbills -- Clippings--includes typescript report, annotated (Box 69)
  - Subseries IX.27: The Shyster
    - Correspondence -- Background: "Manna Falls for Moses," a play by Aaron Hoffman -- Worksheets -- Scripts: -- --Script A (2 copies) -- --Script B -- --Script C (2 copies) -- --Script D (2 copies) -- Legal--contracts -- Playbills (Box 70)
  - Subseries IX.28: Spring Song
    - Correspondence -- Summary (film, 2 copies) -- Worksheets -- Scripts: -- --Script A -- --Script B (3 copies, 2 annotated) -- --Script C (annotated) -- --Script D -- --Script E (2 copies) (Box 71)
    - --Script F (2 copies) -- --Script G (annotated, incomplete) -- --Script H (2 copies, both incomplete) -- --Script I (2 copies) -- --Script J -- Legal--contracts -- Financial--misc. -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Other: Radio ad script; Mailing list -- Printed Material: The script in book form is bound with and filed under Boy Meets Girl. (Box 72)
  - Subseries IX.29: Two Blind Mice
    - Correspondence (3 folders) -- Worksheets ("How to Make a Woman Happy") -- Summaries: Summary A ("How to Make a Woman Happy, 2 copies); Summary B (film, 2 copies) -- Scripts: -- --Script A -- --Script B (British adaptation) -- --Script C ("How to Make a Woman Happy" film 3 copies, 1 annotated) (Box 73)
    - Legal--contracts -- Financial--box office statements, misc. -- Playbills -- Clippings: In English; Foreign -- Other--Columbia University donation slip, not filled out, used as a book mark in printed script, saved for humor value -- Printed Material: -- --Script printed in Theater Arts Magazine (2 copies) -- --Script in book form (3 editions, 2 copies of one) -- --Script in book form (Zwei Blinde Huehner, German) (Box 74)
  - Subseries IX.30: Under the Sycamore Tree
    - Correspondence 1950-1976 (26 folders) -- Worksheets -- Scripts: -- --Script A ("Look to the Ant" annotated) -- --Script B ("look to the Ant" 2 copies, 1 annotated) (Box 75)
    - --Script C (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- --Script D (Italian) -- Legal--contracts (2 folders) -- Financial--misc. (Box 76)
    - Photos--performance with Alec Guiness, other performances -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Other: Production information; Alec Guiness information; Bella's introduction to play, annotated manuscript; Misc.--includes menu of honorary dinner -- Printed Material: -- --Script in Italian printed in Sipario magazine -- --Script in book form--American edition (2 copies); British edition (2 copies); German edition ("Liebe=X") (Box 77)
  - Subseries IX.31: The War Song